As we age, even if we’re healthy, the heart just isn’t as efficient in processing oxygen as it used to be.
随着年龄增长，即使身体健康，心脏处理氧气的效率也不如从前了。
In most people the first signs show up in their 50s or early 60s.
对大多数人来说，最初的迹象在五十多岁或六十岁出头时出现。
And among people who don’t exercise, the changes can start even sooner.
而在不锻炼的人当中，这些变化甚至可能来得更早。
“Think of a rubber band.
“想想橡皮筋吧。
In the beginning, it is flexible, but put it in a drawer for 20 years and it will become dry and easily broken,” says Dr. Ben Levine, a heart specialist at the University of Texas.
起初，它很有弹性，可要是把它放在抽屉里20年，它就会变得干燥、容易断裂，”得克萨斯大学的心脏病专家本·莱文博士说。
That’s what happens to the heart.
心脏的情况正是如此。
Fortunately for those in midlife, Levine is finding that even if you haven’t been an enthusiastic exerciser, getting in shape now may help improve your aging heart.
值得中年人庆幸的是，莱文的研究发现，即使你过去并不热衷于锻炼，现在开始健身也可能有助于改善你日渐衰老的心脏。
Levine and his research team selected volunteers aged between 45 and 64 who did not exercise much but were otherwise healthy.
莱文和他的研究团队挑选了一批年龄在45到64岁之间的志愿者，他们平时锻炼不多，但其他方面都很健康。
Participants were randomly divided into two groups.
参与者被随机分成两组。
The first group participated in a program of nonaerobic exercise—balance training and weight training—three times a week.
第一组参加了一项无氧运动计划，内容为平衡训练和力量训练，每周三次。
The second group did high-intensity aerobic exercise under the guidance of a trainer for four or more days a week.
第二组则在教练的指导下进行高强度有氧运动，每周四天或更多。
After two years, the second group saw remarkable improvements in heart health.
两年后，第二组的心脏健康状况有了显著改善。
“We took these 50-year-old hearts and turned the clock back to 30- or 35-year-old hearts,” says Levine.
“我们让这些50岁的心脏时光倒流，变回了30或35岁的心脏，”莱文说。
“And the reason they got so much stronger and fitter was that their hearts could now fill a lot better and pump a lot more blood during exercise.”
“他们之所以变得强壮、健康得多，是因为他们的心脏现在充盈能力大大增强，在运动时也能泵出多得多的血液。”
But the hearts of those who participated in less intense exercise didn’t change, he says.
但他说，那些参加低强度运动的人，心脏没有发生变化。
“The sweet spot in life to start exercising, if you haven’t already, is in late middle age when the heart still has flexibility,” Levine says.
“如果你还没有开始锻炼，那么人生中开始锻炼的最佳时机是中年后期，那时心脏仍有弹性，”莱文说。
“We put healthy 70-year-olds through a yearlong exercise training program, and nothing happened to them at all.”
“我们让一些健康的70岁老人参加了为期一年的运动训练计划，结果他们身上什么变化都没有发生。”
Dr. Nieca Goldberg, a spokeswoman for the American Heart Association, says Levine’s findings are a great start.
美国心脏协会的女发言人妮卡·戈德堡博士说，莱文的研究发现是一个很好的开端。
But the study was small and needs to be repeated with far larger groups of people to determine exactly which aspects of an exercise routine make the biggest difference.
但这项研究规模较小，需要在规模大得多的人群中重复进行，以确定锻炼方案中究竟哪些方面作用最大。